Mind the lasers, Lord Duke.
You may trigger the alarm.
Please go through the--
How did you get in here?
How did you bypass my security system?
As you can see, it wasn't that secure.
Still, I assure you it'll be much easier
to steal Lady with an Ermine.
Will it?
Aim for his head.
What are they doing here?
Waiting for you.
We could have left as easily as we came in
and be already 500 km away
with your Modigliani and your Rembrandt.
I'd estimate this collection is worth
over a billion euros.
Then why phone me instead of leaving?
Because there's something
I need you to understand.
In this business,
there's a fundamental element, trust.
Now you know that I'll do that job
and that I'm an honorable partner.
And you know my loyalty is above
the billion euros
I could have stolen from you.
Answer it, please.
This is your home.
- Hello.
- It's Santos, sir.
Some men want to rob you.
They shot me, kidnapped me,
and stole my truck, the bastards.
They have all the keys to your estate.
I know, Santos. I know.
I know them.
Everything's in order, all right?
From now on, these gentlemen
are welcome in my estate.
For fuck's sake.
Goddammit.
Hey! Kid?
You see, there was a misunderstanding.
Come, I'll help you up.
Get away from him.
Hands on your fucking head.
Go inside.
I'm impressed
by the lengths you went to
to earn my trust, and,
honestly,
you have.
- Sherry?
- Please.
Sherry.
Now that we're beginning
to enjoy this friendship, Lord Duke,
may I ask something?
Of course.
What do you do here,
with this magnificent collection,
in this cozy room, with a bed…?
I spend more nights than you'd think here.
This is
my secret place.
Well, not anymore.
It's exclusively dedicated
to beauty.
Do you know what beauty is?
I have a vague idea.
To me, it's waking up in that bed,
with my wife,
and allowing
the light of dawn
to come in through that skylight
and illuminate…
Vermeer's The Concert.
It thrills me to think
I'm the only person
on the face of the Earth
who can feel
the joy of contemplating it.
To know that this collection
is just for me.
As if Raphael,
Monet, or Caravaggio
had painted… for me.
When people have a lot of money,
they spend it on what pleases them.
They buy houses, yachts, bunkers.
I have my golden sand,
the aroma of my wine casks, my bulls,
and I have…
my collection.
Is this a satisfactory explanation?
Come with me.
Fuck me. Why won't you listen, dammit?
I'll be damned.
You're late to the party.
Don't you see I was helping him?
Think I'll believe you?
After you almost bit my face off?
But that's over now.
My boss is at the estate with yours.
I just talked to him on the phone.
How? There's no signal at the estate.
Of course not. It's full of jammers.
I called the landline.
Don't move,
or I'll blow your fucking head off.
I just wanted to grab the cell phone
so you can see I'm not lying.
Let me see you.
What's your boss called?
Yeah.
Go to "recent calls."
We can start negotiating.
Do answer. I'm sure it's not for us.
- Hello?
- Good evening.
Is Berlin there?
Oh, well.
It is for you.
- Who's this?
- It's Roi, sir.
The guard says we're with the duke now.
Is that true?
That's right.
What do we do with this guy?
Nothing, Roi. Everything's all right.
We just let him go?
That man must need rest or a doctor.
He's had enough excitement for tonight.
I told you. We're together now.
On the same side.
Not yet.
That's for my time in the river.
We're even for now.
Now we can discuss important matters.
How much will you charge
for stealing Lady with an Ermine?
How about 35 million?
It's not stealing it.
It's planning the heist,
risking our freedom to execute it,
guarding the painting
until we confirm the police have no leads,
and finally, handing it to you, safely,
for your personal enjoyment.
If we bear in mind that the ten
best paid art pieces in history
add up to more than $200 million,
and that Da Vinci is, undoubtedly,
the master of all masters,
I'd say 35 million is even a steal.
Please.
Don't justify yourself.
Did you see me blink?
No, did you?
That means the figure seems correct to me.
I'll also need
four or five million in advance,
in 40,000-euro bundles
of unmarked, nonsequential,
used 100-euro bills.
When you have the money, call me.
I already have that money.
Come to my house
for breakfast tomorrow at 10:00 a.m.
Is that agreeable?
Where will he get
all that money in five hours?
That's not the right question, Roi.
I can answer that.
Those four or five million euros
in nonsequential unmarked bills
won't come from an ATM.
Or from a bank's safe
because today's Sunday.
Unless the guy
has his own money-making machine,
I'd say he has bundles of money hidden
in some mysterious place.
Money of dubious origin. Undeclared money.
No one funds a heist
with their own fortune.
- Now, what's the right question, Roi?
- Where is that dirty money?
Bingo.
That man has a hidden fortune.
He keeps it close. Without paying taxes.
And that's exactly
what we'll steal from that bastard.
It must be a ton of money, right?
His collection has what, 15 paintings?
Say he paid 20 or 30 million for each…
About 300 or 450 million euros.
And where does a Spanish nobleman
such as our duke
get 300 or 450 undeclared millions?
Not from the wineries.
Or from his cattle business.
From the yachts.
Ferrying celebrities back and forth
can't make much.
It can, if you also move something else.
We should look into that, right?
Why would we want to know
where he gets his money?
I am interested.
The more we know about him,
the more we'll have him by the balls.
I'll go.
I can go undercover in one of the yachts.
By myself.
Great.
I'm sorry your reconciliation with Roi
couldn't be,
because I suspect what you want
is not to investigate, but to get away.
Away from him.
Yes.
Then so be it.
No, it's too risky.
She's not going undercover by herself.
If she wants to go, she'll go.
She'll have to grow up sometime.
But since I'm the leader of the crew,
I have the right to know what Roi did
that's so atrocious
you can't even be on the same boat as him.
He pushed me into the void.
You answer, please.
Hello?
Hi, kitten.
Her ex-boyfriend showed up one day.
And that got your blood boiling?
It wasn't me that visit threw off kilter.
Nora told me you lived here.
I told her I was coming to play here
and… coincidence.
Hey.
Why don't you come down?
I can't.
- Who is it?
- Come on down so we can chat for a bit.
I said I'm not going down. Go away.
Our life was a fucking fire, sure.
We should be able
to discuss it face to face.
At that moment,
I should have realized she's sick.
Shut up.
But I didn't see it.
I didn't want to.
You screwed up my life.
Calm down. It's okay.
I won't calm down, dammit!
Not until that guy goes away!
I only wanted to help her.
Dude, she doesn't want to go down.
Let it be.
I'm not leaving
until she comes down, okay?
Help you stop that pain.
Or that rancor, whatever.
Go the fuck away!
Roi, I asked you for help.
Come down! I just want to talk, you hear?
- Calm down, okay?
- I want him to go!
Come down, please!
Breathe.
I'm breathing, Roi, okay?
I won't leave until we wrap up our story,
you hear me?
Someone has to go down.
Or he won't leave.
Go down and rough him up.
I can't.
Why not?
Because it has to be you.
You go and face him.
You can do it.
You're no longer the girl
who fell for him.
You are firm now.
You are brave, dammit.
Look.
You go and tell him it's over.
And close that wound forever.
But that wasn't it.
You didn't want me to close any wounds.
You wanted to look out the balcony
and see how I chose you.
You.
You sent me down
not to overcome my fears, but yours.
Because, deep down, you never trusted me.
Cameron.
I asked you to go down to end a story.
Not to fuck your ex.
This is all your fault.
You forced me.
You sent me to him,
knowing I wasn't capable.
You're a pyromaniac.
No self-control.
So unstable
you're incapable of keeping anything.
Every shitty thing that happens to you,
you deserve.
You destroy everything.
You don't care who you hurt.
I'm giving Jimmy a second chance.
Because giving you a chance
only served to remind me of him.
I don't wanna see you again.
Delete my number and don't look for me.
If you ever see me in danger,
run the other way.
Good morning, Captain.
We have a date.
Oh, do we?
I didn't remember.
Because you didn't know. But I do.
A treat to thank you
for what you've managed.
For risking our lives driving perilously?
And saving you from the police?
For something much better and nicer.
For 24 full hours,
I haven't thought of my ex.
Isn't that incredible?
It is to me.
Come on, take a shower.
I left it all ready for you.
And I got these clothes out
for you to wear.
Try them on.
I don't want you to look out of place.
Out of place where?
That's a surprise.
How did you know I lived here?
I found a mooring invoice
for the boat in your wallet,
and the thought came to me,
"Can he be one of those men
who come to Seville by boat?"
It turns out you were.
- Good morning, miss.
- We woke him up.
Simón, may we talk for a moment?
- Excuse me.
- Course.
One second.
Damián, I'm taking the day off.
A day off?
You're meeting the duke, remember?
To get that thing you asked for.
Four or five million euros
in bundles of 40,000.
I know!
Keila and I worked out the details
for the Ali Baba plan.
Sheer insanity.
I had just gone to bed when she came in.
What the hell's the Ali Baba plan?
An ingenious ploy
that'll lead us to the treasure
when the duke hands you the money.
- Me?
- Damián, I beg you, please.
The hard part is the plan.
That's ready. You'll execute it.
Talk to Keila.
And please,
don't forget to take an elegant bag.
I can't stand thieves
who carry bills in metal cases
as if they were drills.
What will you do?
Embrace life, brother.
And here's the narrowest street
in Seville.
Know what they call it?
Kiss alley.
And…
Do you know why I brought you here?
I haven't the faintest idea.
I'm on tenterhooks.
Let me tell you.
The people
who annoy me the most in the world
are those who save the kiss
for the end of a date.
You don't say.
They annoy me so…
Why?
Because they are people
who live life in fear,
who can't live life to the hilt.
If they have a smidgen of happiness,
they save it for the end.
Just in case.
Just in case what?
In case it gets used up, I don't know.
So they kiss at the end
and go home
with that taste in their mouths.
But I don't think happiness gets used up.
And I, when I really like someone,
I kiss them right away.
And from there, upwards,
like a rocket.
I've wanted to kiss you
since I saw you
flinging things out the window.
And when I went into your house at night.
But it would've been
a bit in bad taste then.
If you'll excuse me, please.
- Step aside.
- Aren't there other streets in Seville?
My God. Walk through.
- There.
- Go.
- There you go.
- Oh.
- This one's a voyeur.
- For sure.
The dog's his cover.
See him looking
from the corner of his eye.
Follow me.
Oh…
Yes, come in.
Could you explain the Ali Baba plan to me?
Know the story
of Ali Baba and the Forty Thieves?
Can't recall much of it.
A man discovers where a band of 40 thieves
keep their treasure.
- Okay.
- Hidden in a cave.
It opens if you stand
in front and say, "Open, Sesame."
Yeah, right.
With me.
- You really don't remember?
- Focus.
What's this fucking Ali Baba plan?
To see where the thieves
keep their treasure.
Only in this case, we're not the thieves.
We're Ali Baba.
Ten sharp.
- Why isn't your boss here?
- He's working on the plan.
I'm his right-hand man
and handle the financial side.
And the details.
I see you brought your own bag.
Yes, I can't stand those thieves
who carry bills in metal briefcases
as if they were drills.
I completely agree.
Good morning.
Darling, the car is at the door.
Looking at you,
I'm tempted to be irresponsible,
but I made these gentlemen get up early.
What will they think of me?
I must attend to them.
He's with another woman
and thinks I don't know.
It's so tiresome to compete
with those perfect ladies…
This one has an ermine.
Samuel, please, escort her.
Gentlemen, I'm off with my babysitter.
Anyway…
Shall we start?
Yes.
Here's the money.
I imagine you want to count it.
Yes, my job is to be cautious.
I have friends
who were paid with photocopies.
It's important you take the bag
you'll use to carry the money.
Why?
Because this bundle will be inside.
The first 40,000.
See anything odd?
Unmarked, nonsequential,
used 100-euro bills.
Where's the trick?
The idea is you'll make a big show
of counting it
and putting it in the bag.
3,960,000.
Until at one point…
4,040,000.
Enough. Return that bundle.
And why would I give him
40,000 euros back?
For a good reason.
That will be the moment for the switch.
The switcheroo bundle
has a long-range GPS chip.
You must hide it
with the money you return to the duke.
So we'll have the location
of that million.
Anything wrong with my money?
No, nothing at all.
For now, we have enough with four million.
You said five million.
We said four or five.
You bringing five
does you credit as a partner.
And speaks to your generosity and fortune.
Was it a test?
Are you evaluating me as a partner?
Me?
Simón told you
this job is predicated on trust.
- Shall I wrap them in plastic for you?
- No need.
Fine. I'll leave it here.
Come.
Girl, good fish today.
Girl!
Do you have Chinese oranges?
Where are we?
In a secret place.
This is a clandestine party
celebrated every year
for the birthday of two aristocrats.
The duchess of Málaga
and the countess of Seville.
Hello. You can't come to the party
on an empty stomach.
People from all classes mingle here.
Aristocrats, bon vivants, artists…
The party lasts 24 hours.
- Shall we?
- Let's.
Samuel, bring me
a glass of godello, please.
I was told it's your birthday.
Happy returns.
I need a word in private.
I'm under constant surveillance.
Third-floor bathroom, the one with
the Niña de los Peines photo on the door.
Wait for me inside in the dark.
And don't lock it.
Excuse me, Duchess.
All clear. You may go in.
Duchess…
You ruined my birthday celebration
with my husband last night.
I'm sorry.
Apology not accepted. You owe me one.
I want you to do a job for me.
I want you
to steal my husband's paintings.
All of them.
I'm sure you'll make excellent business
with them in the black market.
Don't think it's that easy.
I'll give you a tip for your troubles.
A million euros in cash.
I don't know if I'm comfortable
with the term "tip."
You'll have it easy. I'll help you get in.
Genoveva, I know the way.
We got in yesterday, without help.
You seem contrarian.
You are overlooking a little detail.
I am a gentleman.
And I gave your husband my word.
Not just me. My partner did too.
I like your partner.
He seems intelligent.
I'm sure he'll realize that my business
proposition is the interesting one.
Much more than what Álvaro
asked you to do.
There's undoubtedly
something intriguing in all this.
If I may, can I ask
why you want to betray your husband?
Have you ever been in love?
I wonder if I have ever not been.
When I was 15,
I studied at school
every afternoon from 5:00 to 7:00.
And at 5:30, the boys
from the French school would come over
to ride horses.
We had big stables at my school.
Álvaro was always late
to his riding lessons.
Do you know why?
Instead of going straight to class,
he'd climb a stone wall
to watch me study.
For half an hour…
One hour…
And I never noticed.
Until one day, Sister Inés began to throw
stones at him so he'd get down.
No one's ever looked at me like him.
And he's done it for 20 years.
Until now.
Now his eyes are for his collection.
That's why it must disappear.
What do you expect will happen?
Have you wondered what'll happen
if, even after the art is gone,
he doesn't look at you?
What do you mean?
That maybe your husband started
to feel passion for those works
because he stopped feeling it for you.
Maybe life is not
about killing the lover, you see?
But about making it so they choose us
among so many appetizing people.
What an elegant way to refuse me.
I won't deny that you made me think.
You may even have sparked an idea.
But I hope you know that, in negotiations,
I'm as relentless as my husband.
And you won't leave this party
without accepting my assignment.
Because…
with the police hot on your trail,
I don't think you can steal
Lady with an Ermine.
Keila, we're out of the palace.
Does the tracker work?
Yes. The chip is active,
and the money hasn't moved from the room.
Bruce, Roi, when it leaves the palace,
follow it.
Keep your distance, some 400 or 500 m.
No need to take risks.
Keila will guide you.
- Yes.
- Damián, you need to come right now.
- Where are you?
- At a party, in a bathroom.
The duchess brought me here
to offer me a million euros, get this,
to steal her husband's paintings.
- Why?
- Says he no longer has eyes for her.
Only for the paintings.
- What madcap idea is that?
- No, wait.
She also says
I'm not leaving until I accept,
and we won't steal Lady with an Ermine
with the police watching us.
She threatened you?
What will you do? Accept?
Of course not!
Because you'll show up with all your magic
and get the idea out of her head.
- What?
- Listen to me.
You'll go to Santa Cruz Square,
to the orange stall,
and tell the two women at the back
that you want Chinese oranges.
You hear me?
What is it? Do you hear me?
Well, well.
Candela.
What a surprise. What are you doing here?
Waiting for me?
Of course I am.
So, I'm here now.
Is there anything else
you don't leave for the end of a date?
One more thing.
Want to know what?
Are you still up for it?
You great pig.
You think I was born yesterday?
After kissing me in the alley,
which is a commitment,
you got in here with the duchess.
- No.
- With my spittle still in your mouth.
Don't deny it. I saw you with my own eyes.
She beckoned with her finger
as if she were Cleopatra,
and you ran after her.
Fine, the duchess
asked to see me in private, and I agreed,
because I know her husband.
And I intuited
she wanted to discuss something personal.
Important. Tragic, even.
In the end,
she just wanted to talk business.
No, what are you saying?
Business with a lady in a bathroom?
Business? What business?
Backtrack. What business
does one discuss in a bathroom?
Illegal stuff, dammit.
Wouldn't it be leisure?
That's right, leisure.
Take the lesser charge. You're getting
into dicey territory. You'll screw us.
Fine, you're right.
The duchess brought me here,
making me believe she wanted
to discuss something urgent, but she
tried to kiss me.
I, of course, said no.
Excuse me, I want…
Chinese oranges.
What? Will you keep lying to my face?
He did nothing.
Are you an altar boy now?
You don't know
who you're talking to, right?
Huh? What is it?
You're not used to a woman like this.
You can't handle her that easily.
Since you've followed her movements
and mine with such attention
and you want so badly to suspect me,
I'll tell you something.
We were here no more than three minutes.
Enough time to reject a person,
but, you'll have to agree,
not to… satisfy them.
Oh, you silver-tongued devil.
Are you a defense attorney now?
I'll tell you something.
I'll believe you
because no man comes that fast.
And I hope you don't either.
But if you're not going to live up
to that kiss you gave me,
I'd rather you left
and didn't call me again.
I can't believe it.
Are you carrying what I think?
You must be something else
to bring a bag with millions
to a flamenco shindig.
Or I have a festive spirit
and know that the safest place
to keep money
is on oneself.
Play along.
Samuel, we were just wondering
if there wouldn't be
anything more spirituous to drink.
Get us two gin and tonics?
With squeezed lemon
and Madagascar black peppercorns.
Thank you.
It'll take him a while
to find the Madagascar black pepper.
Why exactly are we running?
To lose my babysitter.
I'm confused, and I need clarity.
This way. To the upper floor.
I had an epiphany talking to your partner.
Come this way.
Make yourself comfortable.
Tell me about that epiphany.
I think your partner and my husband
are exactly the same.
The thought crossed my mind, I admit.
And you and I, well…
we take a step back
to let the person we love shine.
That's sexy somehow.
What's sexy about that?
A man sure of himself
doesn't need to be reminded all the time.
He's not constantly trying to surprise
and doesn't go around boasting
about their eccentricities.
We could say
we're like the B-sides of some records,
which are authentic hidden gems.
What do you say to starting a revolution?
You and I.
The revolution of the B-sides.
- Want to betray your husband?
- Until a moment ago, yes.
I wanted to steal his collection
so he'd look at me.
An act of desperation.
But revolution starts with oneself, right?
I've always been a faithful wife,
in love.
I won't be that anymore.
Your friend made me think.
Maybe my husband and I
are no longer in love.
And maybe…
Maybe
it's a good time
to start a new chapter in my life.
Shall we get emancipated together?
You and I.
We can make a record with two A-sides.
Yours and mine.
Sorry, I'm not much of a music lover, and
I'm not sure I understand you.
When I was looking at the Macarena,
I asked her to please help me figure out
what to do with my life.
And you appeared.
You, with your grace,
your poise…
That elegant bag full of millions.
Don't you think that's a strong signal?
I really think
you're the perfect other half
to start my revolution…
and make my debut as an unfaithful wife.
What do you say?
I think your watch is vibrating.
It's a call.
Excuse me.
"Put in your earpiece."
Yes, Keila.
The money's moved, but inside the palace.
Maybe the duke
is packing the bundles again
or bagging them.
I don't think so. It's underground.
I lost the signal
26 meters under the palace,
below what the blueprints
show as the chapel.
But the plans
show nothing under that chapel.
Unless…
He has a vault under his palace.
And that's why you lost the GPS signal.
- Roi.
- Still in position.
Go with Keila and scour the registries
for any info on that chapel.
Bruce, you too.
Copy. Going to the boat.
Hello.
Hi.
- Hi.
- I have a surprise for you.
I'm in Seville.
I'm looking at your boat.
Hello?
Good afternoon, everyone.
I met this goddess only a few hours ago,
but I've already experienced more emotions
than many married couples
by their 50th anniversary.
I could be dead, burned, imprisoned,
and practically divorced, but
she gave me a chance.
And to celebrate it,
I've asked her to sing this song.
Give her a big hand.
Come on!
That's it!
Olé!
Hey.
We have the coordinates
to Ali Baba's cave.
Very well. Where is that lair?
At the duke's palace. Under the chapel.
He must have a vault.
We lost the signal
at the depth of a fourth floor.
So we have located our loot.
Now we only need to go and grab it.
How wonderful.
I love this place.
And the duchess?
Did you talk her out of that absurd idea?
- That one, yes.
- Good.
Now she wants to betray him
with an affair. Says I'm her other half.
It's the third time I've seen her,
and she's saying the Macarena
signaled I was to be her lover.
She leaned in to whisper,
and I had to roll my sleeves down
to hide my hair standing on end.
She wants to make a record of A-sides
with me. I don't know what to say.
The lady unsettles you.
Don't worry. That's all good news.
Keep her eating out of your hand.
What are you saying?
The better half, pulling the strings.
Get close. Grow distant.
It's your turn to become
a Latin lover, Damián. A predator.
How are you?
With Madagascar pepper.
I heard you were working on my commission.
That's right. I came
because I must ask you for something.
We can't continue working
on our plan on the boat.
So many boards and sensitive material.
It can be seen from the outside.
We'll need a more discreet space.
We thought maybe
your palace's north wing, the tower.
How is everybody?
- Hi.
- Hi, darling.
You know? I decided Simón and his friends
will be our guests at the palace
for a few days.
What do you think?
A very stimulating idea.
I'll have to keep you
on a short leash, huh?
This man just loves to make an escape.
Excuse me, but we're having an affair.
Baby boo.
Well, this…
This is Candela.
Happy birthday.
Thank you.
By the way, Candela,
this is Damián, my partner.
We were discussing some business
with the duke and duchess.
Another? Or the same one you discussed
in the Niña de los Peines bathroom?
No, another one, Candela.
Well…
Don't you and your friend
like your money, huh?
Will you excuse me?
Did I say something wrong?
No.
Have you seen the bag that was here?
What was in that bag? You look worried.
Subtitle translation by:
Soledad Etchemendy